nsoftware.com 2018-10-15

# - Privacy Policy

/n software, Inc. ( **"/n software"** ) has established this Privacy Policy because your privacy is extremely important to us. You provide us with personal information that you expect will be kept confidential. Any personal information that you may provide to us will be used to provide you, our customer, better information, products and services. 

This policy describes how we collect and use your personal information. Please read the complete Privacy Policy, as this Policy applies to anyone who uses this website worldwide. We may need to revise our Privacy Policy at times, and we suggest that you revisit this page frequently to review the most current Privacy Policy. 

## Information We Collect and Store

### Personal Data We Collect

Through your interaction with and use of the /n software website or use of our products, we may collect business relevant personal data, which is information that identifies an individual or relates to an identifiable individual (“Personal Data”). Personal Data may include, but is not limited to, your name, physical address, telephone number, e-mail address, and company affiliation which is generally available on the World Wide Web. We do not collect sensitive or highly Personal Data.

### Information You Provide

We ask you to register or login to your account in certain circumstances, including for example, when you download trial or free software, sign up for newsletter services, download patches, purchase software, register software, use our support forums or contact support. As part of the registration process, we collect Personal Data from you in order to provide service and to validate your access to your purchased products and our forums.

### Lawful Basis for Processing Personal Data

In processing your Personal Data in connection with the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, we rely on the legal basis of Legitimate Interest. We collect Personal Data that is necessary for managing and promoting our business, maintaining a product supplier to customer business relationship which includes but is not limited to; product information and marketing communication, maintaining data and network security, improving website and product performance and customer experience, and preventing fraud and malicious acts.

In addition, Direct Marketing activities using Legitimate Interest as the legal basis uses purchased contact lists or publically available sources of information as contact sources in marketing campaigns.

### Anonymous/Non-Personal Data

In general, you can visit /n software on the World Wide Web or use our products without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself.

Our websites and products collect and store anonymous information about your visit or downloads on an aggregate basis. We may also record the name of your Internet service provider, browser type, and country of origin. We use this information only to measure site activity and to develop ideas for improving our sites and products.

Our desktop and mobile applications collect anonymous information about your use of the application to aid us in planning future improvements. Such information includes technical information about your mobile or desktop device such as the model and software versions as well as information about which features of our applications and services you use and the length of time you use such features. Should you encounter errors in use of the application, the application may report such errors along with information about what activity you were performing at the time. All such data are collected and transmitted anonymously.

We collect this information both directly and via use of third party services such as Google Analytics.

### Information Acquired From External Sources

/n software Marketing conducts outbound marketing campaigns to reach new customers. The source of the contact information, their Personal Data, comes from trade shows where contact information is voluntarily provided, webinar and seminar registrations, publically available sources such as Linkedin and purchased lists from companies such as Discover.org. The processing of personal data for direct marketing purposes is carried out for a legitimate business reasons. Only contacts who respond positively to the marketing content or who explicitly request to subscribe are maintained in the marketing system.

### Information Associated With You

When you purchase a product, we provide you with a product license or other authorization mechanism to access to the purchased product. We maintain this information to prevent fraud and authorize access to the products you purchased as well as support services associated with your level of purchase. We provide access to this personal data through a customer portal service on our website for you to review, manage, renew your subscription, and obtain access to your purchased products.

If you purchase products through our ecommerce facilities for one year or recurring subscriptions we do not retain your financial information. All payment authorization is performed by a third-party PCI-compliant payment processor in encrypted form that does not retain credit card information.

## How We Use Personal Data

We may use Personal Data in any of the following ways:

  * We may use your Personal Data to process your transactions.
  * We analyze collected Information to better understand your needs and interests in order that we may improve our service to you.
  * We may combine anonymous information with information you provide to provide a more personal experience on our website or in our products.
  * We may use Personal Data to contact you to follow up on service and support requests that you have initiated or to provide services that you request.
  * We may contact you from time to time to inform you about changes in our services, including new product and product version announcements.
  * We post testimonials on our website and in our marketing material that may contain Personal Data. Prior to posting a testimonial we will obtain your consent to use the testimonial information and your name.
  * Should you download trial software, we may contact you for a limited period to communicate with you on the progress of your trial or to provide you with product education material.
  * We host webinars and other events that may be of interest to our community, and we may contact you about such events if we feel they may be of interest to you.

We will not use or disclose Personal Data to third parties except:

  * to our authorized Sub-processors as necessary to provide services or products you have requested;
  * any third party who holds your information as agreed to comply with the EU GDPR requirements for handling EU personal data;
  * in other ways described in this privacy policy or to which you have otherwise consented;
  * in the aggregate with other information in such a way so that your identity cannot reasonably be determined (for example, statistical compilations);
  * as required by law, for example, in response to a subpoena or search warrant;
  * to outside auditors who have agreed to keep the information confidential;
  * as necessary to protect the rights, safety, or property of /n software, its users, or others; this may include (for example) exchanging information with other organizations for fraud protection and/or risk reduction.
  * as necessary to enforce the Terms of Service.

## Marketing Communication

You will receive product and services information, special offers, and general marketing material as a customer or interested party of /n software's products and services. If you don't want /n software to send you e-mail or postal mail regarding /n software's products, services, or special offers, you may unsubscribe at any time. Unsubscribe links to eliminate further email communications are available on all e-mail communication material. 

For /n software product owners, trial users, or seminar/webinar registrants, some material is not subject to Unsubscribe such as communication related to product downloads, sales transactions, trial requests, software updates, support related information, software patches, fixes or responses to support issues, confirmations for seminars and webinars, disclosures to comply to legal requirements and quality assurance surveys.

## Control & Access to Personal Information

You may find out how much personal information we have about you at any time by requesting that information from /n software. You may change any of your personal information at any time or request to be removed from our mailing list by sending an email to info@nsoftware.com.

## Security of Your Personal Data

Your Personal Data is held on limited access servers at /n software in the United States. We take reasonable steps to protect the Personal Data provided to us from unauthorized access and disclosure.

In the course of using certain of our applications and services, you may provide our applications or services with access to your data (including files and Personal Data), either locally on a device or remotely on servers. Where our applications access your Personal Data, we do so only for the purpose of providing the service. Our applications may store your data locally on your device, for the purpose of improving the performance of the application. Where we do store such Personal Data, it is stored securely.

If you choose to use our support services, you may post information on our support forums or submit information at your discretion in order to more fully describe a problem. Such information may include files containing Personal Data or programs. Information that you post on the support forums is publically available to those who have access to the forums and it is your responsibility to ensure it does not contain personal or sensitive information.

## Revision of Personal Data

/n software retains minimum Personal Data that is reasonable and expected in the management and maintenance of a product supplier to customer relationship. /n software customers may review and update their profile and subscription information on the /n software website customer portal.

If you have issues revising your Personal Data, send mail to privacy@nsoftware.com and state your need and contact information for help.

## Retention and Deletion of Personal Data

/n software will retain your Personal Data for as long as your account is active; as needed to provide you products or services; as stated in the Terms of Use agreement; as needed for the purposes outlined in this policy or at the time of collection; as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, honor UNSUBSCRIBE requests, resolve disputes, meet financial audit requirements and enforce our agreements; or to the extent permitted by law.

If requested, /n software will delete your Personal Data in a manner designed to ensure that your identity cannot be reconstructed or read. A deletion request may not result in the complete deletion of your data. Purchase information will be maintained for legal and financial audit purposes. Forums submissions will be retained as per the Terms of Use Agreement and your name will be removed. If you wish to remove your Personal Data, send an email to [privacy@nsoftware.com](mailto:privacy@nsoftware.com) with “Subject: Remove My Personal Data” and state your need and contact information.

## Personal Data Transfer, Processing and Storage

We process and store data about you on servers located in the USA. Your Personal Data may therefore be transferred to, using appropriate security protocols, processed and stored in a country different from your country of residence, and be subject to privacy laws that are different from those in your country of residence. The Personal Data that we store is not highly sensitive and is required to conduct normal and expected business practices. Specifically, Personal Data, as described in this policy, is stored on US-based data servers or in Cloud Storage Services managed by US and International companies. We and all third party companies with which we engage with have committed to complying with the 2018 EU GDPR privacy regulation for EU residents. Based on the Lawful basis definition, as defined by the EU GDPR regulation, /n software's use and storage of minimal Customer Personal Data, the Legitimate Interests basis is the appropriate legal basis of data storage and use. It is a reasonable and expected use of customer and prospective customer data.

## Use of Cookies

/n software uses cookies to ensure that the content we publish on our site is what our customers need and want. Cookies are small text files that are used to identify users as they access information throughout our site. When someone enters our website, a cookie is placed on their machine (only if the person accepts cookies) or is read if the person has previously visited our website.

Our cookies do not track or collect any personal information. They are used to provide our customers with the most useful information through understanding what areas of our site receive the most traffic and interest.

If you choose to disable cookies on your computer browser, you may not be able to fully access all of the products or services found on our site.

## Third Party Links

/n software's website contains links to other sites on the Internet. We do not share your personal information with those sites, nor are we responsible for the content on their websites.

## Children

Our website does not target nor is it intended to attract children under 13 years old. /n software does not knowingly solicit, collect, or accept personal information from children under 13 years of age.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

/n software will occasionally change and update this Privacy Policy. Any changes made to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this site. If we make any substantial changes in our Privacy Policy, we will post a notice on this site.

## Submissions

/n software will treat any remarks, suggestions, requests or ideas communicated to /n software through this website as non-confidential. /n software will be entitled to use any such submissions for any commercial or other purpose whatsoever, without compensation to you or any other person sending the submission.

## Terms of Use

Our Terms of Use is subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Contacting Us

For questions or concerns about your Personal Data, review, correction, or deletion of your Personal Data you can contact us at [privacy@nsoftware.com](mailto:privacy@nsoftware.com). Please be sure to include your name, company name, email address, telephone number and your specific question, comment or concern.
